M. L. Parrish Collection of Victorian Novelists, 1806-1958 (bulk 1830s-1930s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 1: Artwork and Manuscripts, 1700-2999; 13 boxes
  - Subseries 1B: Bound Manuscripts, 1700-1951; 148 volumes
    - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863, 1852; 1 volume
      - "Letter and Drawings", 1852; 132; 1 volume / 8 leaves
        Bound volume containing an autograph letter from Thackeray, signed with initials and dated 1852. Together with two original pencil sketches: a half length figure resembling a character from "The Virginians"; sketch of Napoleon in characteristic pose, beside two faces of Italian brigands. Also includes an original pen-and-ink sketch for the figure of Mr. Osborne in the illustration "Mr. Osborne's welcome to Amelia"; another sketch of Mr. Osborne in pencil, with two partly finished figures on same sheet.
    - Thirkell, Angela Mackail, 1890-1961, 1951; 1 volume
      - "The Duke's Daughter", 1951; 133; 12 vols (Volume 1-6, Volume 7-12)
        Autograph manuscript of "The Duke's Daughter," written in pencil in 12 notebooks.
    - Trollope, Anthony, 1815-1882, 1800-1909; 9 volumes
      - "Australia and New Zealand", 1873; 137; 2 volumes (Volume 1, Volume 2)
        Corrected page proofs in unknown hand. London: Chapman and Hall.
      - "Calendar of Anthony Trollope Letters in the Parrish Collection", 1900s; 134; 1 volume / 36 leaves
        Typed index of the Trollope correspondence found in the Parrish Collection, compiler unknown.
      - "Contract Concerning 'Ayala's Angel", 1881 August; 139; 1 sheet / 4 pp.
        Autograph agreement with Chapman and Hall publishers regarding "Ayala's Angel."
      - "Death of Commodore Goodenough", 1800s; 26; 1 volume / 10 leaves
        An autograph manuscript of his Letter XVIII, "The Death of Commodore Goodenough." Written on 5 pp., royal tissue paper in pencil and 4 pp. royal paper in ink, signed at the end. Approximately 3,300 words. Each leaf is marked "Duplicate" and on the verso of the last leaf is a note to that effect, also giving the title, n.d. Together with a corrected galley proof.
      - "An Eye for an Eye", 1870s; 138; 1 volume / 262 leaves
        Complete autograph manuscript of "An Eye for an Eye," with annotations and corrections. Written in 1870 but not published until 1879.
      - "Letters", circa 1839-1882; 135; 3 volumes (Volume 1, Volume 2, Volume 3)
        Three volumes of signed autograph letters from Trollope. Letters are tipped in and accompanied by a typed transcription.
      - "South Africa", circa 1874; 140; 1 volume / 144 pp.
        Autograph notes pertaining to "South Africa."
      - "Travel Diaries", 1841 September 15 - 1871 September 18; 136; 6 volumes (Volume 1, Volume 2, Volume 3, Volume 4, Volume 5, Volume 6)
        Six manuscript travel books, dated from. As a member of the postal service, Trollope kept in these books a record of the distances he had traveled to determine his travel allowance. After he retired from the service, he continued to use the books as a travel record. He also recorded in them other income.
      - "Zulus", 1879 October 23; 141; 1 volume / 43 leaves
        Autograph manuscript of a lecture on the Zulus delivered in Nottingham.
    - Trollope family, 1870-1879; 1 volume
      - "Villa a Ricorboli", 1870s; 143; 1 volume / 11 leaves
        Contains eleven photographs, by "L. Powers, Photographe, Florence" of Thomas Adolphus Trollope's villa, and of views from the villa, near Florence owned and occupied by him from 1865 until 1872, after he had sold the Villino Trollope in Florence following the death of his first wife, Theodosia Garrow.
    - Wills, William Henry, 1810-1880, 1850 March 30-1859 May 28; 1 volume
      - "Office book of 'Household Words", 1850 March 30 - 1859 May 28; 142; 1 volume / 122 written leaves
        Office book, almost entirely in the hand of W. H. Wills, assistant editor of Dickens's magazine called "Household Words." Records for each issue the date, serial number, author of each contribution (the contributions are anonymous in the periodical itself), its title, length in columns, price paid, date of payment, and memorandum. Dickens is always referred to as "Mr. C. D." and the record shows that he was not paid separately for his many contributions, which were doubtless regarded as part of his editorial work.
    - Wilson, William, 1851; 1 volume
      - "A Little Earnest Book", circa 1851; 127; 1 item / miscellaneous paging miscellaneous paging
        Contains letters and clippings concerning the work "A little earnest book upon a great old subject" by Wilson. Compiler unknown. Contains 19 ALsS from Edward Lytton (3); William Wilson (1); Robert S. Mackenzie (3); Alfred Jackson (3); Charles F. Ellerman (1); William C. Bennett (1); [W] Sharp to Effingham Wilson (1); Le Page (1, incomplete); Thomas Carlyle (1, with envelope); Camilla Crosland (1); Alfred [Elmes?] (1)' [Ch.Ch.] Bradley (1); A. & C. Black to Effingham Wilson (1); L. Wilson [sister] (1, with on 4th page undated letter from his mother, M. Wilson); William Gurner (1).
  - Subseries 1C: Miscellaneous, 1775-2999; 1 box
    Consists of miscellaneous papers of the Trollope family, Charles Reade, and Charles Dodgson (Lewis Carroll).
    - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge (Lewis Carroll), undated; more than 3 boxes
      - Photographs, undated; L1-L43; 3 boxes (Box 109, Box 110, Box 111)
        Photographs L1-L16: box 109; Photographs L17-L32: box 110; Photographs L33-L43: box 111
        Access to the loose Carroll photographs in Series 1 is restricted because the original photographs have been reproduced in full in the Edward Wakeling "Catalogue of the Princeton University Albums" in Roger Taylor and Edward Wakeling, Lewis Carroll Photographer (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 2002). Researchers and those seeking photoduplication are advised to use the published catalogue. Color transparencies and black-and-white photo prints are also available for reference use, and thumbnails of all photographs are in the Portfolio database of the Special Collections, available online at http://libweb2.princeton.edu/rbsc2/portfolio/portfolio.html. Researchers who feel they have a compelling reason to be granted access to these original photograph albums must request permission in advance from the Curator of Manuscripts ( http://www.princeton.edu/~rbsc/contact/index.shtml ).
        Lewis Carroll loose photographs, as identified in the Edward Wakeling "Catalogue of the Princeton University Albums" in Roger Taylor and Edward Wakeling, Lewis Carroll Photographer (2002): L(1-43) ["Loose Photographs"]. There are seven additional miscellaneous photographs.
      - Falconer Madan material, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 1)
      - Mathematical Manuscripts, Nos. 1-62, undated; 4 boxes (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous Material, undated; 1 box (Box 5)
        notes on loose photographs
        copy of will, "Proved May 13th 1898," 1 p.
        sample of Carrollian chintz fabric
        "List of Lewis Carroll Items, Property of Morris L. Parrish, Loaned to Wesleyan University, Middletown, Connecticut, for Centennial Anniversary Exhibition, October, 1931," 10 pp. (photostats)
    - Reade, Charles, undated; 1 box (Box 6)
      - Corrected page proofs for The Cloister and the Hearth, undated; 1 box
    - Trollope Family Literary Papers, 1873 June 15-1947 June 26; 2 boxes (Box 7, Box 8)
      Includes acrostics, poems, plays, translations from Italian, etc., some by Frances Eleanor Trollope, a few printed items, photographs, postcards, and later papers on spiritualist seances. AM 21442. In 2 boxes.
      Note: The following box and folder list has been retyped from Alexander D. Wainwright's original typewritten list, dated 11/15/1988.
      - "The Wisdom of the Dove. A dramatic sketch in one act." MS. 28 leaves. On verso of final leaf: 8 (?) Ashburn Place S.W., undated; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - "An Italian view of The duties of constitutional Sovereigns." MS. 37 leaves. Signed at end: J.J. Mottershed, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - "Baby Barton's Secret from the French." MS. 3 pp. Signed F.E. Trollope, 1891 October 28; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - "To our Navy and our Army." MS. 9 pp. Signed F.E. Trollope, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - "Two Votes and a Veto. An unofficial conference." MS drafts. 10 p. Unsigned, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Various drafts of poems, etc. Unsigned, undated; circa 23 pp. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - 9 acrostics. MS., dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - "The Swan, the crab, & the pike." MSS of poem. 1 p. 2 versions. Signed FET. Rome, 1898 April; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - "Dramas by Daylight. No 1. A Broken Thread." Typescript with some MS changes. 29 leaves, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - "Circumstances alter cases. A commedietta in one act." MS. 83 leaves, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - 2 uncorrected galleys of Mrs. Trollope (alternative titles): Lieutenant Giles' Christmas Eve in Anson Street, Two Uncles, Uncles Neville and Uncle Giles. 1 complete, 14 sheets; 1 incomplete, 13 sheets, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Carte de visite photographs, and other photographs and pictures (none identified as members of the Trollope family). 22 items, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - "The Wisdom of the Dove. A dramatic sketch in one act." MS. 38 leaves, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - "Lines written for little boy's album. Margate. 1877." MS. 2 pp., dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Notebook containing notes on seances, with some fragments of MS. 2 calling cards of clairvoyants, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - In front: Album of postcards of scenes in France and Belgium, some addressed to Miss Gladys Wharton Robinson, Mr. & Mrs. E.B. Reece, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8)
      - Laid in: photograph of Geoffrey Wharton Robinson in uniform, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 8)
      - Too Clever by Half. A Comedy in Three Acts. (Printed at the G.M. Industrial Home.), dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8)
      - Revue des Deux Mondes, 1873 June 15. Contains "Le Chagrin de Tante Marguerite," p. (815)-858, a reduction in translation of Frances Eleanor Trollope's Aunt Margaret's Trouble, portion of 1 box (Box 8)
      - Large envelope of "Records of sittings (by Mrs. G.W.Reece) with mediums, Private ones and for G. Baker"; Mrs. Reece's Laundry Book, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 8)
      - Corrected galley of Mrs. F.E. Trollope's "Two Uncles." 14 sheets, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - "A Spring Storm." Poem translated from the Russian. MS. 1 p. Signed F.E.T. Rome, 1898 April; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - "The Army." Typescript of poem. 1 p. by "J.E. Trollope." 2 copies, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - "A Toast to our Navy & Army. Christmas 1911." MS. 8 pp., undated; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Pencilled record of a sitting, 1931 November 6; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - TLS from Bradford A. Booth to Mrs. Reece, 1947 June 26; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - "The Rocking-horse." MS of a poem. 1 p., dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - "A Broken Thread." Typescript of a play. 20 leaves, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Unfinished watercolor of a Chinese scene, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - "To our Navy and our Army. The Navy." Typescript. 1 leaf. 2 copies. 4 printed fragments, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Calling card of Mrs. Rowland Taylor, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - "A Slight Mistake." MS. At head of p. 1: Mrs. T. Adolphus Trollope. c.o. G. Wharton Robinson Esqr. 27. Sutherland Avenue W. 130 leaves, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Act 1 of a play set in "Morning room in Gerard West's country house in Surrey." MS. 59 leaves, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - "Il Canto dell'Amore. Translation." MS. 7 leaves, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - MS of an essay, in ink, 21 leaves. At head of p. 1, in pencil: Mrs. T.A. Trollope 27. Victoria Grove I think I should like the title Right about Face!, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Trollope Family Additional Papers, 1775-2999; 2 folders
      Acquired from the estate of Robert Arthur Cecil (1921-1994), great-grandson of Thomas Adolphus Trollope. AM 1996-59. In 2 boxes.
      Note: The following box and folder list has been retyped from an original typed list, dated 10/3/1996.
      - Lists of descriptive material, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Blessington, Marguerite Gardiner, Countess of, 1789-1849; portion of 1 folder
        - AL to Theodosia Garrow, 1838 November 19, 3 pp., with envelope, portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Cecil, Beatrice Stuart-Wortley, 1881-1973; portion of 1 folder
        - 7 photographs and other portraits, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Eliot, George, 1819-1880; portion of 1 folder
        - AL to Beatrice Trollope, 1876 December 1, 2 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Landor, Walter Savage, 1775-1864; portion of 1 folder
        - ALS (initials) to My Dear Friend, undated, 2 pp. Probably addressed to Joseph Garrow, portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - ALS to Joseph Garrow, Thursday Night, 3 pp. Defective with loss of text, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - ALS to Theodosia Garrow, postmarked 1839 December 6, 3 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - ALS to Theodosia Garrow, postmarked 1839 December 14, 3 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - ALS to Theodosia Garrow, 1847 January 23, 1 p., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - AMs, [of Theodosia Garrow's poems], 3 pp., undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - W.S. Landor Criticism, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Lawley, Francis Charles, 1825-1901; portion of 1 folder
        - ALS to his mother, Caroline, Lady Wenlock, St. Louis, 1862 February 2, 4 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Robinson, Ellen Lawless Ternan, 1839-1914; portion of 1 folder
        - 7 letters to Mr. & Mrs. Charles Stuart-Wortley, circa 1913-1914; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Copy of telegram, Charles and Alice Stuart-Wortley to Mrs. Robinson, 1913 June 17; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Copy (ALS), Charles Stuart-Wortley to Mrs. Robinson, 1913 July 2, 2 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900; portion of 1 folder
        - ALS to Lady Castletown, [Venice, 1876], 1 p., undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Stuart-Wortley, Beatrice Trollope, 1853-1881; portion of 1 folders
        - ALS to Louisa, n.p., Friday night, undated, 4 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - ALS to Violettina, 39, Montagu Square, Tuesday morning [ 1879 November 4], 8 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - ALS to Kereline, Rome, 1880 January 9, 4 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Letters addressed to her, 1876 December 19-1879 October 11; portion of 1 folder
          - Isa Blagden. ALS, undated, 4 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 10)
          - John Ruskin. ALS, 1876 December 19, 1 p., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 10)
          - Maria Ternan Taylor. ALS, 1879 October 11, 2 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - 6 verses by or inscribed to her, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - 4 watercolors, with an ALS, Charles Lindsay to Charles Stuart-Wortley, April 7, no year, sending one of them to him, portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - 18 photographs and other portraits, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - One negative, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - Program. R. Teatro delle Legge, Florence, 5 March 1873. Firenze: Società Tipografica-Editrice. Bice Trollope in the role of Henriette in Molière's Les Femmes Savantes, Act 3, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Stuart-Wortley, Charles Beilby, Lord Stuart of Wortley, 1851-1926; portion of 1 folders
        - Letters addressed to him by, 1882 November 7-1912 March 30; portion of 1 folder
          - Hester Mulock Austin: 4 ALsS, with two enclosures, one being a copy of ALS, F.E. Trollope to Alfred Austin, 1892 March 16; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 15)
          - Amy Audrey Locke: ALS, 1912 March 30, 1 p., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 15)
          - Sir William Frederick Pollock: ACS, 1882 November 7; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 15)
          - Maria Ternan Taylor: 2 ALsS, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - 4 photographs, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Trollope, Anthony, 1815-1882; portion of 1 folders
        - 4 letters to Charles Stuart-Wortley, 1881-1882; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - 2 letters to Mrs. James Stuart-Wortley, 1881; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 18)
        - 3 letters to Beatrice Trollope, 1865, 1878, 1879, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 19)
        - 2 cartes-de-visite photographs, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Trollope, Lady Cordelia Maria, 1822-1909; portion of 1 folder
        - 2 letters to Charles Stuart-Wortley, [1881], undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Trollope, Frances Eleanor Ternan, 1835-1913; portion of 1 folder
        - 40 ALsS to Charles Stuart-Wortley, 1883-1912; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 22)
        - ALS to Mrs. Charles Stuart-Wortley, 1891 April 10, 3 pp., portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 22)
        - Telegram to Charles Stuart-Wortley, 1894 August 2; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 22)
        - Undated Memorandum from Frank N. Parsons with "enclosed photograph" (present), portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 22)
        - Charles Stuart-Wortley. ANS, 1913 June 17; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Trollope, Frances Milton, 1780-1863; portion of 1 folder
        - Paris and the Parisians. Preface to the second edition. AMs, London, 1836 May 16, 8 pp. With an engraved portrait of the author, portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - Trollope, Francis Charles, 1857-; portion of 1 folder
        - 3 ALsS to Charles Stuart-Wortley, 1881; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Trollope, Henry Merivale, 1846-1926; portion of 1 folder
        - 4 ALsS to Charles Stuart-Wortley, 1882 (2), 1886, 1892, portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Trollope, Rose Heseltine, circa 1821-1917; portion of 1 folder
        - 7 letters to Charles Stuart-Wortley, 1899 (4), 1901 (3), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Trollope, Theodosia Garrow, 1825-1865; 2 folders (2 partial)
        - Poems, undated; portion of 1 folder
          - "In the noon-day's golden pleasance," AMs, 2.5 pp., dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 27)
          - "Baby Beatrice," AMs, 4 pp., dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 27)
          - "Baby Beatrice," AMs, corrected draft, 4 pp., undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 27)
          - "Magnetismo d'Amore," AMs, 1 p., undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 27)
        - 20 watercolors and drawings, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Watercolor of a man and a woman, unsigned, with lower left corner burned (?) away. Inscribed on verso: "Recollections of a Fete Villa Salviati: Florence. J[-].", dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Watercolor of two women, unsigned, with lower left corner burned (?) away. Inscribed on verso: "Recollections of a Fete Villa Salviati: Jun[-].", undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Watercolor of a paunchy man, unsigned. In pencil in upper left corner: Captn. Hardchett (?), dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil sketch of Joseph Garrow, signed Eugenia Latilla. With a presentation inscription from the artist to Mrs. Trollope, Florence, 1851 June 23; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil sketch of Theodosia G. Trollope, reclining. Inscribed on mount: Füssli and dated Florence Jany. 1862, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil sketch of H.B. Stowe, signed T T and dated, 1857; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil sketch of R.L. Shiel, signed T.G., dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil sketch of Thiers, signed T T and dated on mount Sant' Andrea, 1852 May 9; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - John Cook of Exeter. Pencil sketch of a man in uniform, uttering a condemnation of those who laugh when a man is being tried for his life, unsigned, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pen-and-ink sketch of Edmond Grainger of Exeter, unsigned, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pen-and-ink sketch of two men, unsigned, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Watercolor of "Grand Festa Nazionale Octr 5, 1856 Corse à Fantini," unsigned, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil sketch of a woman, unsigned, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil and watercolor drawing of a stout woman, inscribed: "She's all my Fancy painted her!" Casino Ball, Jany. 3d, 1852; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil sketch of Lady C. Fleming, unsigned, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Watercolor drawing of Lady C. Fleming, unsigned, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil drawing of a man and woman in Renaissance dress, on stiff dark paper, unsigned, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Watercolor drawing of a woman holding a child, inscribed on verso: Full length portrait of Beatrice Catharine Harriet Trollope in the eighth month of her age Novr. 1853, unsigned, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil sketch of the head of a man, inscribed: F T -- Florence 1848 May 22. Two rough pencil sketches on verso, portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - Pencil sketch of a banjo player, signed T G T (?), dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 9, Folder 28)
        - 17 pen-and-ink drawings to illustrate Canzoni Popolari Toscani, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Documents and obituaries, undated; portion of 1 folder
          - Certificate (true copy) of her marriage to Thomas A. Trollope, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 10, Folder 2)
          - True copy of certificate of birth of Beatrice ("Bice") Trollope, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 10, Folder 2)
          - True copy of certificate of burial of Theodosia Trollope, dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 10, Folder 2)
          - 8 newspaper clippings on death of Theodosia Trollope, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 10, Folder 2)
          - Handwritten copy of inscription on Villino Trollope ("Given to Bice ... in May or June 1881"), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - 3 cartes-de-visite photographs, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Trollope, Thomas Adolphus, 1810-1892; portion of 1 folders